<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello and welcome to my blog-profile-thing. on Tom Elliott</title>
    <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello and welcome to my blog-profile-thing. on Tom Elliott</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 21:37:24 +1200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomelliott.co.nz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bus Display v2 with React, D3, and Mapbox</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2021/04/bus-display-v2-with-react-d3-and-mapbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 21:37:24 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2021/04/bus-display-v2-with-react-d3-and-mapbox/</guid>
      <description>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been learning React, a javascript framework for building responsive user interfaces (the long game is iNZight-built-with-React, but that&amp;rsquo;s a long way off). The best way of learning something is by mini-projects, so recently that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing! So, when it was pointed out to me last week that my bus display in the University of Auckland&amp;rsquo;s Science Buildling is broken&amp;mdash;turns out it has been since January!&amp;mdash;I thought &amp;ldquo;Ooh, another mini-react-project!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting bus arrival in real-time (is hard)</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/nzsa-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 16:10:00 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/nzsa-2020/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;In which I give a very basic overview of my main methods and results in a quick 15-minute presentation at the 2020 NZSA UnConference! For more details, you may consult my thesis (code and PDF available from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmelliott/phd-thesis&#34;&gt;tmelliott/phd-thesis&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building my new website</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2020/09/building-my-new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 09:00:41 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2020/09/building-my-new-website/</guid>
      <description>Several years ago I decided to redesign my website (mostly as a way of learning new web technologies), but what I came up with was ... rather uninspiring. Ever since reading about Hugo, I&#39;ve wanted to build my website using it (including designing my own theme and templates), but between the PhD and iNZight, I seldom felt like spending my free time doing even more coding! In recent weeks, I&#39;ve had a slight break from working and found the inspiration to finally get around to the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocketing Into Spring</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2020/08/rocketing-into-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 14:21:40 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/2020/08/rocketing-into-spring/</guid>
      <description>During the first Kiwi lockdown, I planted some rocket seeds. I&#39;ve enjoyed several harvests, but it appears that lengthening days have triggered baby-making-mode. Suddenly my stubby rocket plants have sent a long proboscis-like stem into the sky and have started to produce little flowers.
 
 In the photos you can see the long main stem (left) shooting up to over 30 cm tall! The last week has been very rainy in Auckland (and I was a little preoccupied with my PhD defense) so I was a little surprised to see everything booming (and even blooming!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the prediction of bus arrival using real-time network state</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-defense/</guid>
      <description>My PhD defense presentation is linked below. You possibly won&#39;t understand most of it, however, since there&#39;s no recording available and most of the text needs to be accompanied by talking!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the travel time of transit vehicles in real-time through a GTFS-based road network using GPS vehicle locations</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/anzjs2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 11:11:33 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/anzjs2020/</guid>
      <description>Predicting the arrival time of a transit vehicle involves not only knowledge of its current position and schedule adherence, but also traffic conditions along the remainder of the route. Road networks are dynamic and can quickly change from free‐flowing to highly congested, which impacts the arrival time of transit vehicles, particularly buses which often share the road with other vehicles, so reliable predictions need to account for real‐time and future traffic conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iNZight: Behind the Scenes</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/satrday-akl-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/satrday-akl-2020/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about iNZight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel times and bus prediction</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-talks-day-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 15:20:55 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-talks-day-2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical data based priors for better bus arrival-time prediction</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/user-conf-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 15:17:34 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/user-conf-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How can we improve bus ETAs?</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/isba-conf-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 15:15:53 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/isba-conf-2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time transit network modeling for improved arrival time predictions</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/nzsa-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 15:11:45 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/nzsa-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting bus arrival using estimated road network state</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-talks-day-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 15:08:39 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/phd-talks-day-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The path to computational statistics</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/statistics-teachers-day-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 09:05:20 +1200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/statistics-teachers-day-2017/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
