<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>web app on Tom Elliott</title>
    <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/tags/web-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in web app on Tom Elliott</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:57:23 +1300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tomelliott.co.nz/tags/web-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IDI Search App</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/idi-search-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 09:57:23 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/idi-search-app/</guid>
      <description>The IDI Search App allows researchers to explore what variables are available in the IDI, and provides descriptions and SQL information about each variable. The app uses Data Dictionaries from Statistics NZ to collate collection, dataset, and variable information, which is stored within a relational database. The front end is powered by NextJS, allowing us to provide an interface for users to list all variables or, more usefully, those variables, datasets, and collections that match a specific search term.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disclosure Risk Calculator</title>
      <link>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/disclosure-risk-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 10:45:04 +1300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tomelliott.co.nz/publications/disclosure-risk-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Before a dataset is made public, it needs to be checked to ensure no individuals are at risk of being identified. We developed this calculator to quickly assess a dataset for disclosure risk based on a selection of variables.
There are two aspects to the calculator:
1. Overall risk This is the risk of disclosure given the currently chosen variablse and sampling fraction. The calculations here use only information about the number of unique and paired observations, and is easily performed in the browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
